# **Blake Ahalt**

■ blakeahalt@gmail.com □ 508-299-9373 • Los Angeles, California

■ blakeahalt.com in/blakeahalt github.com/blakeahalt

### **PROFILE**

Software developer with 12+ years of teaching experience and a passion for technology, learning, and problem-solving. Motivated to expand upon experience building four full-stack applications using JavaScript, React, Express.js, Node.js, SQL, MySQL, SQLite, Python, Flask, and MongoDB. Strong communication skills with experience building positive relationships among students, parents, teachers, and school administration, in addition to leading and training teams of teachers. Seeking a software development position to apply my skills and experience in independent and collaborative settings.

#### **PROJECTS**

# Portfolio Site | React.js, Responsive Design | blakeahalt.com

2023

- A personal portfolio site that showcases my projects, artwork, and blog, while implementing responsive design.
- Runs on a Virtual Private Server and served with Nginx.

# NFT Tracking Tool | React.js, Express.js, Node.js, MySQL | blakeahalt.com/nftpage

2022

- An application that allows you to track the top trending NFT collections and individual sales using various API data.
- Consolidated data from multiple APIs (<u>CryptoSlam, NFT Stats, OpenSea</u>) to track top daily, weekly, and monthly NFT sales.
- Implemented JSON Web Tokens allowing protected routes to be accessed by both registered users and Google account users.
- Created a user registration feature that securely stores Argon2 encrypted passwords in a MySQL database.
- Implemented Google Cloud OAuth 2.0 allowing users to register and log in with their Google accounts.

# Stock Trading Application | Python, Flask, SQL | blakeahalt.com/stockpage

2022

• A stock portfolio application that can store and update user transactions with real-time stock quotes from the IEX Cloud API.

#### Country and Weather Application | JavaScript, Node.js, React.js | blakeahalt.com/countrypage

202

- A React application that displays country facts and weather forecasts using two APIs (restcountries.com, openweathermap.org).
- Implemented responsive web design to make it mobile-friendly and optimize the user experience on multiple devices.

### Phonebook CRUD Feature | MERN stack | blakeahalt.com/phonebookpage

2022

- A CRUD phonebook feature that adds contacts built with a MERN (MongoDB, Express, React, Node.js) stack.
- Implemented responsive web design to make it mobile-friendly and optimize the user experience on multiple devices.

# COURSEWORK

# Harvard CS50x: Introduction to Computer Science | HarvardX/EdX | [CERTIFICATE]

Mar 2022 - Jun 2022

• Applied C, Python, SQL, HTML, CSS, and Javascript to efficiently solve problems related to abstraction, algorithms, data structures, resource management, security, software engineering, and web development.

#### Full Stack Open 2022 | University of Helsinki | [CERTIFICATE]

Current

• Currently building single-page applications with React.js using REST APIs and Node.js. Sections also cover GraphQL, MongoDB, testing, configuration, and environment management.

## **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

JavaScript, React, Node.js, Express.js, Python, Flask, SQL, MySQL, SQLite, MongoDB, Git, OAuth2, JSON Web Token, Jest, Cypress, HTML5, Front End Design, Back End, Full Stack, Responsive Design, Bootstrap.js, webpack

### **EDUCATION**

### University of San Francisco | San Francisco, CA

2006

Bachelor of Arts in Visual Art, Minor in Mathematics

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

# Kindergarten Teacher | Village School | Pacific Palisades, CA

Aug 2017 - Jun 2021

- Taught students to meet their academic, social, and emotional needs through independent and collaborative teaching methods.
- Communicated with students, faculty, parents, and administration to ensure clear expectations in and out of the classroom.

### Lead Teacher | Chungdahm Learning & Pride J Academy | Seoul, South Korea

Aug 2008 - Dec 2016

- Developed a 2nd-grade curriculum, created its supplementary materials, and led four other 2nd-grade teachers.
- Improved the performance of over 15 teachers through time management evaluations, methodology accuracy assessments, and classroom control training, achieving the highest retention rate among seven local branches for over three years.